Imagine, if you will -- a gift.
تصوروا .. معي .. هدية
I'd like for you to picture it in your mind.
أريدكم ان تتخيلوها في عقولكم
It's not too big --
انها ليس كبيرة جداً
about the size of a golf ball.
وهي بحجم كرة الغولف
So envision what it looks like all wrapped up.
حاولوا تخيل ماهية هذه الهدية المُغلفة
But before I show you what's inside,
وقبل ان اريكم ماذا يوجد في داخل هذه الهدية
I will tell you, it's going to do incredible things for you.
سوف اخبركم .. كيف ان هذه الهدية قامت بأشياء رائعة من اجلي
It will bring all of your family together.
وكيفها انها جمعت عائلتي معاً
You will feel loved and appreciated like never before
وكيف بدأنا نشعر بالحب والتقدير كما لم نشعر من ذي قبل
and reconnect with friends and acquaintances
وكيف ساعدت على اعادة احياء التواصل مع الاصدقاء والمعارف
you haven't heard from in years.
الذين لم تتحدث معهم منذ سنوات
Adoration and admiration
وكيف ساعدت على غمرك بمشاعر
will overwhelm you.
الحب والتقدير
It will recalibrate what's most important in your life.
وكيف اعادت الى نظرك أهم الاشياء في حياتك
It will redefine your sense
وكيف اعادت تعريف مفاهيمك
of spirituality and faith.
عن الايمان و الروحانيات
You'll have a new understanding
وكيف صنعت تفاهم جديد
and trust in your body.
بينك وبين جسدك !
You'll have unsurpassed vitality and energy.
وكيف اشعلت الحيوية والطاقة الغير مسبوقة في حياتك
You'll expand your vocabulary,
وكيف وسعت حصيلتك اللغوية
meet new people,
وعرفتك على اشخاص جدد
and you'll have a healthier lifestyle.
وساهمت في صنع نمط صحي اكثر في حياتك
And get this --
تخيلوا هذا ..
you'll have an eight-week vacation
سوف تحصلون على عطلة من 8 اسابيع
of doing absolutely nothing.
لكي تقوموا بلا شيء !
You'll eat countless gourmet meals.
وسوف يتاح لكم اكل ما لذ وطاب من الطعام
Flowers will arrive by the truckload.
والزهور سوف تُلقى على جانبكم بعربات النقل
People will say to you,
وسوف يقول لك الجميع
"You look great. Have you had any work done?"
أنت تبدو بصورة رائعة .. هل قمت بعمل ما ؟
And you'll have a lifetime supply
سوف تحصل على كل ما تحتاجه في حياتك
of good drugs.
من المخدرات !
You'll be challenged, inspired,
وسوف يتم تحديك .. و إلهامك
motivated and humbled.
وتحفيزك .. و تشعر بالتواضع
Your life will have new meaning.
سوف تمتلك مفهوماً جديدا
Peace, health,
للسلام .. وللصحة
serenity, happiness,
للصفاء .. للسعادة
nirvana.
للنيرفانا
The price?
ما هو سعرها
$55,000,
55000 دولاراً
and that's an incredible deal.
وهي صفقة رائعة جداً
By now I know you're dying to know
اعتقد انكم تتحرقون شوقاً لمعرفة
what it is and where you can get one.
ماهي هذه الهدية .. وكيف يمكن الحصول عليها
Does Amazon carry it?
وان كان بالامكان الحصول عليها من خلال موقع آمازون
Does it have the Apple logo on it?
وهي هنالك شعار آبل عليها
Is there a waiting list?
او هل هنالك قائمة انتظار للحصول عليها
Not likely.
في الحقيقة لا ..
This gift came to me about five months ago.
لقد حصلت على هذه الهدية منذ خمسة شهور
It looked more like this when it was all wrapped up --
وقد بدت هكذا .. وهذا غلافها
not quite so pretty.
لا تبدو جميلة في الواقع
And this,
وهذه أيضاً ..
and then this.
وهذه
It was a rare gem --
لقد كانت جرثومة نادرة
a brain tumor,
سرطان دماغي
hemangioblastoma --
ورم أرومي وعائي
the gift that keeps on giving.
انه هدية .. تعطيك الكثير .. بدون توقف
And while I'm okay now,
حتى بعد شفائك منها
I wouldn't wish this gift for you.
انا لا اتمنى حصولكم على هكذا هدية
I'm not sure you'd want it.
ولا اعتقد ان احدا منكم يرغب بها
But I wouldn't change my experience.
ولكن هذا لن يغير من تجربتي معها
It profoundly altered my life
لقد غيرت حياتي بصورة تامة
in ways I didn't expect
بصورة لم اكن اتوقعها على الاطلاق
in all the ways I just shared with you.
لقد أحببت ان اتشارك معكم .. كيف تغيرت حياتي بشتى الطرق
So the next time you're faced
لكي .. عندما تواجهوا أمراً
with something that's unexpected,
مشابهاً .. غير متوقع .. يوما ما
unwanted and uncertain,
أمراً .. غير مرغوب .. غير مفهوم
consider
إعتبروه ..
that it just may be a gift.
انه قد يكون هدية قد أُهديت لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)